

### Profile

I'm Roger, a UX/Strategic Designer and Researcher based in Porto Alegre (Brazil). I spent the last 14 years researching, developing and solving problems for digital interfaces, brand internacionalization and media, services and product projects for some of the biggest B2B companies in Brazil. I work in the way of user centered design and data research aligned with design thinking and agile methodologies.



## Main Skills —

- Strategic Design Research
- Lead Designer / UX / UI
- User Behaviour Research
- Front-End Development
- DesignOps
- Design System
- Analytics, Data Analysis



## Tools & Languages —

- Figma, Framer
- Google Data Studio
- HTML5, CSS 3, JavaScript
- Hotjar
- Grunt, Gulp, Sass, LESS
- Python
- VS Code



## Work Experiences

June 2021 - Current

SellersFunding LCC New York, USA



## Head of Product / User Experience

I work as lead designer on Daily Advance Product researching and development improvements based on data analisys;

- **UX** Research
- Data Analisys
- A/B Testing
- Process Modeling

- A/B Testing
- Design System
- **User Stories**
- High Fidelity Prototypes With Framer and Figma

#### Jan 2021 - June 2021

Santander Group



UX Designer and researcher for the internationalization of payment methods

- UX Research
- Data Analisys
- A/B Testing
- Process Modeling

## High Fidelity Prototypes

With Framer and Figma

#### Feb 2020 - Jan 2021

Unicred do Brasil Porto Alegre (BRA)

## Lead Designer

Lead designer on mobile banking application and PIX implementation

- UX Research
- Data Analisys
- A/B Testing
- Process Modeling

- Product Owner (PIX)
- DesignOps
- Design System
- Team Management

#### Jan 2016 - Feb 2020

Magna Studio Porto Alegre (BRA)

## Partner and Head of Design

Design and Tech Leader in technological projects for B2B retail companies.

Research

- UX Lead
- Project Management
- Tech Lead
- DesignOps Leader
- Data Analisys

#### Jun 2008 - Jan 2016

Navent / Imobex / Net One Buenos Aires (AR) = Miami (USA)

## Full Stack Designer

Lead designer and Front End Developer for real estate digital services and tools.

- UX Design and Research
- Innovation Leader
- Front End (JS, CSS, HTML)
- Prototyping
- SEO

## **Education and Certifieds**

- Master in Service Design
  - Politecnica di Milano (Milan) 2020/2023
- Specialization in Service Design
  - Politecnica di Milano (Milan) 2017/2020
- Bachelor in Strategic Design
  - Unisinos (Porto Alegre) 2011/2015
- Designer Certified by Apple
  - Apple Developer Academy (Porto Alegre)

## Languages & Extras

- Portuguese: Native
- Spanish: Fluent
- English: Advanced
- Motion Graphics
- High Presentation Skills
- Design Certified by Apple(Developer Academy)

# Design Methods

- Design Thinking
- Double Diamond
- Lean Inception
- Design Sprint
- Blueprint Development

- Benchmarking
- Territorial research
- A/B Test Specialist
- DesignOps
- Design System

# Other skills

- Research Methods (Psychology and Design)
- Consumer Behaviour Researcher
- High skills with Framer (React components)
- Spark AR Specialist
- Lean Inception Certified
- Design Certified by Apple (Dev. Academy)
- Product Owner

- Full Stack Design (Next.JS, Node, Front)
- Google Data Studio Specialist (Python)
- Jira, Azure and Git
- Product/Branding Strategies
- Tech Leader for Front-end
- Design Lead